Steven H. Scheuer Papers
Steven H. Scheuer Papers
1939-1996
Scheuer, Steven H.
294 linear ft.
Research files, correspondence, photographs, clippings, press releases, reviews, writings (scripts, story proposals, articles), printed material, and miscellanea from the American movie and television historian and critic.
2534369
Biographical History
Steven H. Scheuer is a movie and television historian and critic. He was the editor of Movies on TV (originally titled TV Movie Almanac & Ratings) which went through 17 editions between 1958 and 1993. The first guide of its kind (it preceded the still-active Maltin's TV Movies and Video Guide by ten years), the book contained a mixture of movies, videos and TV movies with ratings up to four stars.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Steven H. Scheuer Papers contains research files, correspondence, photographs, clippings, press releases, reviews, writings (scripts, story proposals, articles), printed material, and miscellanea. The collection is partially processed and the inventory below is to the box level.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is partially processed. For the most part original order has been retained.
Related Material
See also the Steven H. Scheuer Television History Interviews.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Scheuer, Steven H.; Popular culture -- United States.; Television -- United States.; Research notes.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Press releases.; Reviews (documents); Scripts (documents); Articles.; Printed materials (object genre); Critics.; Writers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Steven H. Scheuer.
Inventory
- All About TV
  - Research files
    - A-F (Box 1)
    - misc (Box 2)
  - Show files
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - 1979-1983 (Box 4)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 6)
    - misc (Box 7)
    - misc (Box 8)
  - General files (Box 9)
- Baseline, Inc
  - General files (Box 10)
- Cable Key
  - 1981 (Box 11)
  - 1982-1984 (Box 12)
  - Research files, 3 boxes (Box 13-15)
- Movies
  - Research files by title
    - AA-AN (Box 16)
    - AB-BA (Box 17)
    - AN-AY (Box 18)
    - BA-BE (Box 19)
    - BI-BL (Box 20)
    - BO-BY (Box 21)
    - BU-CA (Box 22)
    - CA-CH (Box 23)
    - CI-CO (Box 24)
    - CO-DI (Box 25)
    - CR-DE (Box 26)
    - DE-DO (Box 27)
    - DO-EL (Box 28)
    - DR-FO (Box 29)
    - EM-FA (Box 30)
    - FR-GE (Box 31)
    - FB-FO (Box 32)
    - GH-GR (Box 33)
    - GR-HA (Box 34)
    - HA-HE (Box 35)
    - HI-HU (Box 36)
    - I-IN (Box 37)
    - IN-JE (Box 38)
    - JE-JU (Box 39)
    - KA-LA (Box 40)
    - LA-LI (Box 41)
    - LI-LO (Box 42)
    - LO-MA (Box 43)
    - MA-ME (Box 44)
    - MI-MY (Box 45)
    - NA-NJ (Box 46)
    - NI-OM (Box 47)
    - ON-OX (Box 48)
    - PA-PH (Box 49)
    - PI-PR (Box 50)
    - PR-RA (Box 51)
    - RA-RE (Box 52)
    - RE-RO (Box 53)
    - RU-SC (Box 54)
    - SE-SH (Box 55)
    - SH-Z (Box 56)
    - SH-SM (Box 57)
    - SN-SS (Box 58)
    - ST (Box 59)
    - ST-TH (Box 60)
    - SU-SW (Box 61)
    - SW-TH (Box 62)
    - TH-TR (Box 63)
    - TH-WH (Box 64)
    - TR-VI (Box 65)
    - VE-WH (Box 66)
    - WH-WO (Box 67)
    - WO-ZU (Box 68)
    - BI-UR, 1989-1991 (Box 69)
    - unsorted, 4 boxes (Box 70-73)
  - Research files general (Box 74)
  - File cards (Box 75)
  - Mss for Movie Guide (Box 76)
- Radio TV Daily
  - General files, 1939; 1943 (Box 77)
  - Subject files
    - A-G (Box 78)
    - G-Q (Box 79)
    - R-Z (Box 80)
  - Research files
    - CA-DUZ (Box 81)
    - EA-HAR (Box 82)
    - MAS-POZ (Box 83)
    - PRA-STRA (Box 84)
    - TUI-Z (Box 85)
  - Correspondence
    - Alphabetical, mixed, 5 boxes (Box 86-90)
  - Correspondence by state (Box 91)
  - Photographs by subject
    - A-LY (Box 92)
    - M-Z (Box 93)
    - misc (Box 94)
  - Printed material
    - 1951-1964 (Box 95)
    - misc, 2 boxes (Box 96, 97)
  - Research files, A-Z (Box 98)
- Scripts and story proposals
  - misc, 7 boxes (Box 99-105)
  - Hello World (Box 106)
  - by Scheuer (Box 107)
  - by Scheuer, 2 boxes (Box 108, 109)
- Soap Opera Scene
  - 1976-1981 (Box 110)
  - 1981-1983 (Box 111)
  - 1982 (Box 112)
  - 1990-1996 (Box 113)
- TV Key
  - Audio tapes (Box 114)
  - Clippings, 2 boxes (Box 115, 116)
  - Correspondence
    - 1950s (Box 117)
    - misc (Box 118)
  - Features (Box 119)
  - Features (Box 120)
  - Keynotes
    - 1954-1957 (Box 121)
    - 1958-1964 (Box 122)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 123)
    - 1967-1970 (Box 124)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 125)
    - 1975-1978 (Box 126)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 127)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 128)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 129)
    - 1987-1991 (Box 130)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 131)
    - 1992-1994 (Box 132)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 133)
    - unsorted (Box 134)
  - Local
    - 1956-1959 (Box 135)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 136)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 137)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 138)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 139)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 140)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 141)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 142)
  - Local/Metro, 1974-1977 (Box 143)
  - Metro, 1982; 2 boxes (Box 144, 145)
  - Mailbag
    - 1953-1964 (Box 146)
    - 1956-1962 (Box 147)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 148)
    - 1967-1970 (Box 149)
    - 1971-1976 (Box 150)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 151)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 152)
    - 1981-1996 (Box 153)
  - Keynotes & Mailbag, 1978 (Box 154)
  - Mimeo
    - 1960-1963 (Box 155)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 156)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 157)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 158)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 159)
    - 1974-1976 (Box 160)
  - Movie Preview, 2 boxes (Box 161, 162)
  - Original
    - 1955-1957 (Box 163)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 164)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 165)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 166)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 167)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 168)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 169)
    - 1974-1976 (Box 170)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 171)
  - Photos
    - 1950s-1960s (Box 172)
    - 1950s-1960s (Box 173)
    - misc (Box 174)
  - Press releases, 1980-1981 (Box 175)
  - Previews
    - 1955-1958 (Box 176)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 177)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 178)
    - 1970 (Box 179)
    - 1971 (Box 180)
    - 1971 (Box 181)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 182)
    - 1979 (Box 183)
    - 1980 (Box 184)
    - 1982 (Box 185)
    - 1982 (Box 186)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 187)
    - 1990-1996 (Box 188)
  - Radio copy (Box 189)
  - Wire copy (Box 190)
  - Witbeck reviews (Box 191)
  - General files, A-Z (Box 192)
  - Research files, 6 boxes (Box 193-198)
  - Mixed editions
    - 1955-1956 (Box 199)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 200)
    - 1975 (Box 201)
    - 1979 (Box 202)
    - 1979 (Box 203)
    - 1980 (Box 204)
    - 1980 (Box 205)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 206)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 207)
    - mixed dates, 6 boxes (Box 208-213)
- TV Watching
  - Program and research files, 2 boxes (Box 214, 215)
- Video buyers service
  - Miscellaneous, 7 boxes (Box 216-222)
- Manuscripts
  - Miscellaneous (Box 223)
- Personal files
  - Personal business files, 6 boxes (Box 224-229)
  - Personal research files
    - ACLU (Box 230)
    - Broadcasting standards, NBC, 1983; 1986,; undated; radio, television, and advertising; 3 volumes (Box 231)
    - Children & TV (Box 231)
    - Children & TV (Box 232)
    - FCC (Box 233)
    - P (Box 234)
    - Public TV (Box 235)
    - TV, 6 boxes (Box 236-241)
    - General, 5 boxes (Box 242-246)
  - Personal subject files
    - "Law and the Media, New Technology" (Box 247)
    - "Seminars" (Box 248)
    - "Telefilm" (Box 249)
    - "VBS" (Box 250)
    - F-W (Box 251)
    - "Hopewell Productions" (Box 252)
    - misc, 27 boxes (Box 253-279)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous, 16 boxes (Box 280-295)